<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>quantum error processing | QUANTUM</title><link>https://kunwang.info/tag/quantum-error-processing/</link><atom:link href="https://kunwang.info/tag/quantum-error-processing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>quantum error processing</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://kunwang.info/media/icon_hua80fed0d19161674393c832b4a1bafa2_7228_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>quantum error processing</title><link>https://kunwang.info/tag/quantum-error-processing/</link></image><item><title>Quantum Error Processing Toolkit</title><link>https://kunwang.info/projects/qep/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://kunwang.info/projects/qep/</guid><description>&lt;p>I led the development of
&lt;span style="color:#DB4437;">&lt;strong>the first and only open-source Quantum Error Processing (QEP) toolkit in China&lt;/strong>&lt;/span>.
My proficiency in quantum computing has enabled me to identify critical needs and
select the most suitable quantum solutions.
Simultaneously, my expertise in computer science has empowered me to
design robust and efficient data structures, algorithms, and software architectures,
and uphold a well-structured software development life cycle,
ensuring the timely delivery of these solutions with high quality.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>QEP stands at the forefront as an innovative and pioneering open-source quantum error processing toolkit,
representing a core component seamlessly integrated into the
&lt;a href="https://baike.baidu.com/item/%E7%99%BE%E5%BA%A6%E9%87%8F%E5%AD%90%E5%B9%B3%E5%8F%B0" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Baidu Quantum Platform&lt;/a>,
which is a full-stack quantum software and hardware platform developed by Baidu.
This toolkit serves a paramount purpose in characterizing and enhancing the performance of quantum computers
by effectively addressing and mitigating the inherent quantum errors presented in these devices through
sophisticated software solutions.
QEP boasts a comprehensive suite of four powerful quantum error processing tools:
quantum performance evaluation,
quantum error characterization,
quantum error mitigation, and
quantum error correction.
The versatile capabilities embedded in QEP empower our quantum hardware team to engage in a meticulous
and rigorous process of characterizing and enhancing Baidu&amp;rsquo;s quantum processors. By leveraging QEP&amp;rsquo;s advanced tools,
we can delve into the intricate details of quantum performance, understand the characteristics of errors,
implement effective mitigation strategies, and deploy quantum error correction codes.
This comprehensive approach accelerates closed-loop and end-to-end optimizations,
thus playing an instrumental role in advancing the capabilities, robustness, and reliability of
our quantum computing infrastructure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>QEP is officially released at &lt;a href="https://baike.baidu.com/item/%E9%87%8F%E5%AD%90%E5%BC%80%E5%8F%91%E8%80%85%E5%A4%A7%E4%BC%9A" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&amp;ldquo;Quantum Create 2022&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a>,
a grand quantum developer conference held in Beijing.
The release garnered widespread recognition from mainstream news media, including
&lt;a href="https://analyticsdrift.com/baidu-unveils-its-first-superconducting-quantum-computer-qianshi/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">AnalyticDrift&lt;/a>,
&lt;a href="https://en.pingwest.com/a/10696" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PingWest&lt;/a>,
&lt;a href="https://www.toutiao.com/article/7137927453540237838" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Toutiao&lt;/a>,
&lt;a href="https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/6jfh_MMypbqHq3KlhYiTew" target="_blank" rel="noopener">QbitAI&lt;/a>, and many others.
Establishing a robust foundation backed by &lt;strong>5&lt;/strong> research papers and over &lt;strong>50&lt;/strong> patent applications,
the latest version, &lt;a href="https://pypi.org/project/qcompute-qep/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">QEP 1.1.0&lt;/a>,
brings unparalleled versatility to quantum hardware access.
This release significantly expands its support to diverse platforms from five leading companies,
further solidifying its position at the forefront of quantum error processing toolkits.
QEP&amp;rsquo;s modular design, founded on the software design philosophy
of &amp;ldquo;high cohesion, loose coupling&amp;rdquo; for effective code organization and
independent functionalities, features &lt;strong>32&lt;/strong> core modules. With a vast repository housing &lt;strong>26,000&lt;/strong>
lines of open-source code, and an extensive library of &lt;strong>37&lt;/strong> bilingual tutorials,
alongside comprehensive API documentation, QEP is designed to be user-friendly, allowing easy access and utilization of its capabilities.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The success of QEP is indebted to the invaluable contributions of numerous research interns and engineers.
Through effective management and the implementation of a rotation mechanism,
I established a system that facilitated the swift integration of research interns into the project,
enabling them to make meaningful contributions. To date, &lt;strong>12&lt;/strong> research interns have seamlessly
immersed themselves in the realm of quantum computing,
acquiring expertise in both theoretical and practical aspects of quantum error processing.
Their talents have played a pivotal role in driving innovative projects that push the boundaries of quantum technology.
The sustained fascination these interns exhibit toward quantum computing stands as a testament to the passion and
enthusiasm that I have ignited in these future researchers.
This collaborative effort underscores the collaborative and dynamic nature of the quantum research environment
that has been cultivated within the QEP project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The technology landscape of QEP is illustrated as follows.
For more detailed information about QEP, interested parties can
explore the repository on &lt;a href="https://github.com/baidu/QCompute/tree/master/Extensions/QuantumErrorProcessing" target="_blank" rel="noopener">GitHub&lt;/a>
or access the package on &lt;a href="https://pypi.org/project/qcompute-qep/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PyPI&lt;/a>.
These platforms offer in-depth insights into QEP&amp;rsquo;s features, functionalities, implementation guidelines, and user tutorials.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="png" srcset="
/projects/qep/qep-architecture_hu8dff87efc9f81ec7063c32610e170de2_403985_a17b69bcafddc80527447580f7609970.webp 400w,
/projects/qep/qep-architecture_hu8dff87efc9f81ec7063c32610e170de2_403985_c2776e48d283d545ec56c0b62abc7973.webp 760w,
/projects/qep/qep-architecture_hu8dff87efc9f81ec7063c32610e170de2_403985_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w"
src="https://kunwang.info/projects/qep/qep-architecture_hu8dff87efc9f81ec7063c32610e170de2_403985_a17b69bcafddc80527447580f7609970.webp"
width="760"
height="451"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>